Robert Black Civilian Conservation Corps collection 1930s-2000s MS 445
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Robert Black Civilian Conservation Corps 1930s-2000s
Collection Number: MS 445
Black, Robert
4 Linear Feet
This collection contains materials documenting of biographies, interviews and photographs of former CCC enrollees. This collection is arranged by its file formats and subjects including biographies of enrollees’ of Arizona CCC camps, personal and group photographs, slides, cassette tapes, VHS videos, and some memorabilia.
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
None
Biographical Note
Robert Black was a volunteer historian for the National Park Service assigned to the Chiricahua National Monument. During his time there he began to research NM-2-A one of the many camps in Arizona where young people served in President’s Franklin D. Roosevelt’s “tree army” better known as the Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC). Robert Black accumulated a considerable number of interviews and photographs of former CCC enrollees with the intention of one day publishing a commemorative booklet of the NM-2-A.
The Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC) was established by President Franklin Roosevelt in 1933. It was a Depression Era program designed to provide jobs and relief for unemployed youth and their families. The majority of jobs were unskilled manual labor for the purpose of developing the natural resources in rural areas of the United States and its territories. From 1933-1942 there were 52,905 enrollees working in Arizona CCC camps. They built 5,783 miles of forest roads, constructed 3,559 miles of telephone lines and developed numerous recreational sites still used by Arizonan’s today. The program ceased to exist in 1942 when the United States Congress eliminated its funding.
Series List
Series I: Biographies
Subseries 1: Files (alphabetically by last name)
Subseries 2: Cassette tapes
Subseries 3: VHS tapes
Series II: Photographic materials
Subseries 1: Prints: persons and group photos, animals, automobiles
Subseries 2: Slides: Chiricahua national monument, Lichens, Research images, reunion.
Series III: Research files
Subseries 1: C.C.C. government data
Subseries 2: General files
The collection includes C.C.C. former enrollees’ biographical files and general correspondences, people’s photos, slides, cassette tapes, VHS tapes, memorabilia and C.C.C general government enrollment data. The materials are divided into three series: Files, Photographs and Research file. The first series is arranged alphabetically by files’ format. The second series is divided by its formats into two subseries: prints and slides and negatives. Then each subseries is categorized alphabetically by its subjects. The third series is categorized by files subjects.
Civilian Conservation Corps (U.S.) - History.; Civilian Conservation Corps (U.S.) - Newspapers - History - 20th century.; Civilian Conservation Corps (U.S.) - Officials and employees – History - 20th century.; Civilian Conservation Corps (U.S.) - Arizona - Wilcox - History.; Civilian Conservation Corps (U.S.) - Arizona - Chiricahua - History.; Black, Robert.; Camps - Arizona.; Civilian Conservation Corps (U.S.) - Photograph collections.; Chiricahua National Monument (Ariz.).; Historic sites - Arizona - Chiricahua National Monument.; Lichens - Arizona.
Container List
- Series I: Biographies,1940, 1982-2001
  This series contains three subseries which are categorized by format. The first subseries is print materials which is arranged alphabetically by person’s last name. It contains personal correspondence, interviews and print remembrances of former enrollees of the Civil Conservation Corps. from 1986 - 2004. The second subseries is cassette tapes which is arranged by person’s last name as well. The third subseries are VHS tapes.
  - Subseries 1: Files
    - Adams, Carrol, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Adams, Howard, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Albert, Dick, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Amador, Chile, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Anderson, Ruth, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Andress, Norman, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Andrews, Carl, 1997; 1999 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Arnell, Henry, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Avery, Willie E., 1997; 1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Baun, A.L., undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Betancourt, Juan A., 1999 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Barrbee. Henry, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bennet, Herman, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Best, Alfrea, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Baglod, Andy and Naomi, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Bird, Olvis, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Black, Bob, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Boyett, Nell, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Bracamonte, Laundry, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Briggley, Jeff, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Brothers, Larce, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Brunson, Larry, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Burke, Vestal, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Canady, Willis H., 1999 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Cannon, Gene, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Carolan, Owen, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Cary, Donald, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Caum, Rothellen, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Clark, Mackie, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Colbert, Robert, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Colucci, Betty, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Cooley, Glenn L., 1999 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Cooper, Bennie, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Cozby, Homer, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Cortez, Quadalupe, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Coy, George R., 1999 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Crown, Stanely, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Crawford, Ray, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Crow, Homer, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Cyr, Jerome, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Dahif, Janice, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Daut, John W., 1998 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Deal, Walter, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Delgado, Moises, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Divers, Bill, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Dixon, Fred, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Dojaquez, Henry, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Duncan, Henry, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Dynneson, Lawarence, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Ellis, Joe, undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Espe, Jerry V., 2002 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Evenson, Orville, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Fehrencamp, George, undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Fennelly, Bill, undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Fields, Joe, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Flores, Alfred, 1997; 1999 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Flory, Robert, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Foges, Steve J., 1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Foly, Morrison, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Ford, Harold, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Foster, Jack, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Fousell, Vic, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Fraijo, Archimedes, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Franklin, Olin M., 1999 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - French, Larry, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Gadloris, Ann F., 2002 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Garcia, Fred, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Garmon, Paul, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Gastellom, Luis, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Gerault, Leon, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Gilber, G. Marshall, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Grajalva, Jeanette, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Grefthen, Daniel W., undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Grose, James, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Grubb, Glenn E., undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Hamilton, Tommie James, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Hanna, Frank Jr., undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Hansbury, John L., 1998 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Hansler, Mearl E., 1999 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Harris, Majorie, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Harris, Woodie, 1988/1989 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Harwood, Charles W., 1999 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Harttrup, Jeri, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Havacurn, Carlos, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Heaton, Curt, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Herrera, Adolph, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Hester, Floyd E., 1999 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Hill, Henry Y., 1999 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Huffman, Roy, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Hunt, Atta B., 2002 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Hurd, Howard, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Jackson, Lloyd D., 1999 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Jimenez, Richard, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Johnson, Faye, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Johnson, Keith and Joan, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Johhson, Lloyd D., 1999 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Josefow, Edward, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Kase, Ed S., 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Keen, Clinton, undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Kirby, Claudia B., 2000 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Kirk, Mareanne, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Koenig, Leo, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Kraft, Randy, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Lau, Verna M. (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Lee, Judson W., 1997 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Leetch, Preston, undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Lindskog, Harvey, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Lira, Jouguin, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Martan, Earnest, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Martin, Robert T., 1999 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Masters, Carl 1999 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Mathews, Josie, undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Mayfield, Bill, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - McAllister, Harry and Wife, Shirley, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - McBride, Bernard J., 1999 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - McBride, Joe P., 1999 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - McEwen, Jim, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - McGilvray, John L., 1999 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - McLaughlin, Robert L., 1998 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - McNiel, Uriah L., 1940; 1997; 1999 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Melzer, Richard, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Miller, Bob, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Miranda, Eugenio, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Mitchell, Charles K., 1999 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Moore, Wesley, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Morgan, Floyd, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Mundt, Alfred, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Nettles, Robert L., 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Nichols, Adam Miller, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Nicholson, James, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Nicholson, Richard C., 2002 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Noreno, Marcus R., 1999 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Notestine, Jim, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Parrer, Lawarence, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Perilloux, Charles J., 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Peroski, Ellen, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Pierce, Loyd Robert, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Platt, Bradley, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Portwood, Mack C., 1999 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Pursley, Ralph, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Purvis, Louis and Marie, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Ringenbach, Ray, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Redo, A.J., 1998 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Riordan, James, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Roman, Art, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Romero, Marlo, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Ronquillo, Edward B., 1999 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Rowland, Marvin, 1986-1987; 1993 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Rownd, Lionel, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Rust, Donald, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Sanders, Glen J., 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Scitticatt, Mary, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Seaman, Ida, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Shackelford, Harvey, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Simmons, William A., 1999 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Soto, Miguel D., 1999 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Stafford, Ja Hu, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Stainsberry, Dickie, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Steele, R.J., 1999 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Stricht, John, undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Swartz, Carl N., 1994-1999 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Tellez, Frank J., 1999 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Thomason, Jeff P., undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Thompson, Perry, undated (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Turnee, Joe, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Upshaw, Black K., 1999 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Vaughn, Jack, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Vesely, George, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Wallace, Gorden, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Warren, James, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Warren, Roy J., 1999 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Watson, Autumn, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Welker, Doug, undated (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Wells, Burt D., 2002 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Wenger, Alvin W., 1999 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - West, Mary, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Whitecotton, Norace, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Wildey, Walter, undated (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Wilkins, Yvonne, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Willett, Gilbert, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Williams, David H., undated (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Williams, Horace, undated (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Wilson, Donald R., 1998 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Wisner, Robert, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Wright, Melvin, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Wright, R.O., 1999 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Wrolstad, Orville K., 1999 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Young, Darrill, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Youngman, Fred, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Zaida, Charles G., 1999 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Zoller, Richard, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Subseries 2: Cassette tapes: from former C.C.C. members.
    - Interviews through A-M (Box 4)
    - Interviews through M-R (Box 5)
  - Subseries 3: VHS tapes
    - Interviews. (Box 6)
- Series II: Photographic Materials
  This series is subdivided by file formats into two subseries and then arranged alphabetically by content subjects of materials. It contains people’s portraits, group shots, photos with animals and automobiles, and slides.
  - Subseries 1: Prints
    - Animals (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Automobiles (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Group shots, oversize group shots see Box 10 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Landscapes (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Portraits (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 2: Slides and Negatives
    - Chiricahua (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Lichens (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Research (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Reunion (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Series III: Research, 1933-2004
  This series is subdivided by broad theme and then arranged alphabetically by folder name. It contains C.C.C. Camps government data, general files and news clippings.
  - Subseries 1: C.C.C. Camps government data
    - Camps Approved for Arizona, 1933-1942 (Boc 8, Folder 1)
    - Camps buildings/Arizona undated (Boc 8, Folder 2)
    - Camp reports, inspection reports, 1934-1940 (Boc 8, Folder 3)
    - Enrollment data, 1935-1937 (Boc 8, Folder 4)
    - Location and strength of C.C.C.C. in the 8th corps area, 1933-1942 (Boc 8, Folder 5)
    - Menus/Company 828, camp NM-2-A, 1934-1936 (Boc 8, Folder 6)
    - Rosters/Arizona, 1934-1939 (Boc 8, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 2: General files
    - Chiricahua pt.1 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Chiricahua pt.2 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Correspondences, 1986-1988; 1996-1999; 2003 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - General files, 1934-1948 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - News clippings and newspapers, 1933-1948; 1983-2004 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 3: Memorabilia
    - Ephemeral materials including hats, buttons, bricks and certificates. (Box 10)